# William Mayger

Address: 47 Chalfont Drive,

Gillingham,

Kent,

**ME8 9DW** 

Email: will.mayger@theweblancer.com

Github: https://github.com/WillMayger

Website: <a href="http://theweblancer.co.uk/">http://theweblancer.co.uk/</a>

Linked In: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/will-mayger-6aa5659a

Mobile Number: 07514494820

## Professional profile

Git SVN

I have been working in frontend and backend web development for the past 4 years, I love to keep up to date and constantly keep learning. The technology that I have most experience with would be Node.js, however, I have covered a wide range of technical skills throughout this time including:

-	Node.js	-	ES6
-	Javascript	-	Chai
-	React.js	-	Angular
-	Express.js	-	Heroku
-	Less	-	AWS
-	CSS	-	MongoDB
-	SCSS	-	Postgres
-	HTML	-	Web Design
-	Jquery	-	Graphics Design

- Python - Django
- ES6 Photoshop
  Chai Bootstrap
  Angular Responsive websites
  Heroku Java
  AWS C#
  - ASP.NET
     MySQL
     Cloud Foundry
     Flask

I have been implementing these skills in many ways, some from day one such as Javascript, HTML, CSS, Git and JQuery.

Many were by pair programming with expert level senior developers as well as a senior designer in Atos / Canopy whilst using the Extreme Programming Agile Methodology together with test driven development where I have anchored my own team. This was a very close team environment which we all enjoyed and learnt much from each other.

In the team described above, we were using a stack of Node.js, Express.js, Less, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Handlebars, Chai, and Cloud Foundry. In this team we were building a complex UI for Cloud Foundry which is a PaaS. This was also full stack development using Git version Control. For the first couple of months we were using React.js as well.

In Gforces we pay attention to the details, details meaning every pixel has to match the design exactly. For sites we use a few tools but mainly Less, JS and AWS S3 with our own bespoke software for the rest. When we build our tools and software we will tend to use Node.js and we use SVN as version control.

Some sites I have built at Gforces:

- http://www.gcmotors.co.uk/
- http://www.hwm.co.uk/

I create websites privately as well to learn and improve my knowledge and skills as much as possible in web development whilst also trying to grasp knowledge of how to handle and deal with clients, finances and admin related tasks. The last website I made privately was a fitness blog (<a href="http://maygerfitness.co.uk">http://maygerfitness.co.uk</a>) this is mainly using the technology's: JavaScript, Jquery, HTML, Less, Python, Django, Postgres and is being hosted on a heroku server and versioned by git.

I am currently in the process of building a web app for budgeting using a stack off: Node.js, Express.js for the API using OAuth2 for Authentication.

A View Layer of: React.js, Node.js, JS, SCSS, HTML. This also uses git!

I have come to learn that I have a huge passion for creating websites that are always bringing something new to the table and that really help people and it gives me great pride to say I created it. I keep getting great feedback from everyone I have made websites for and I take enormous pleasure from hearing that my hard work is improving other people's lives. I would say I am always trying new ways to do things, that includes technology to rethinking a bit of logic for a fix. I like to actively make sure I am always learning.

## Objective:

I am currently looking for my career to progress to the next stage, so I can use all the skills I have learnt to this point and improve on them, as well as learn new and challenging things, more specifically in the world of frontend / backend Javascript.

### Career summary:

**01/07/2014 - 10/07/2015** - Apprentice Software and Web Developer at Canopy Cloud (ATOS) - PaaS Team

01/07/2015 - 01/03/2016 - Web Developer and Web Designer at Atos / Canopy Cloud (ATOS) - Research, Innovation and Incubation Team

01/03/2016 - 01/07/2016- Web Developer / Web Designer / Engineer at Atos Engineering

01/08/2016 - Current Date - Front End Web Developer at Gforces

**01/01/2016 - Current Date** - Private Web Designer and Developer in free time as <a href="http://theweblancer.co.uk">http://theweblancer.co.uk</a>

#### Education:

- GCSE: English C
- GCSE: Maths C
- GCSE: I.C.T C
- GCSE: Biology C
- GCSE: Chemistry C
- GCSE: Physics C
- GCSE: Citizenship Studies C
- GCSE: Work skills (BTEC) C
- GCSE: Sport (BTEC) C

- AS-LEVEL: Photography A
- AS-LEVEL: Certificate in financial studies A
- AS-LEVEL: Art D
- A-LEVEL: Photography A\*
- A-LEVEL: Diploma in financial studies A
- A-LEVEL: Forensic science Pass
- City and Guilds Software and Web
  - Development level 3

## **Professional Development:**

I started learning Graphics Design in school whilst doing my Photography AS and A Level. This is where I knew I had a passion in creating beautiful looking designs and photos.

After completing A-Levels with an A\* in Photography, I wanted to try something new and give myself a chance to push myself past what I already knew.

I looked to the internet to start learning about coding and web development. Shortly after I got myself an apprenticeship in software and web development. Whilst in this apprenticeship I had courses supplied by QA and work on websites provided by Canopy. However I wanted to expand my knowledge so in my own time I continued looking at blogs, youtube, and sites like codecademy to learn even more. After this I spent many months with a hands on approach to learning by creating websites and software using tools such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Python, Django, node.js and react.js

During my apprenticeship I won apprentice of the year award for innovation.

After my apprenticeship had finished I was taken on as a full time employee where I went into the Research, Innovation and Incubation team where I used the Extreme programming agile methodology. I was closely paring each day with senior developers and a designer in which we used react and node.js to begin with and then changed to using just node.js with express. In my free time I continued to create websites until in the new year a local cricket club needed a new website creating. From this point onwards I have been doing private work in my free time which has really expanded my skills and knowledge.

After, I was moved into Engineering within Atos which was solely setting up servers where I then moved my career to Gforces.

In Gforces our main aim was to create pixel perfect responsive

websites for some huge clients in the vehicle industry. The websites we make have to work for every pixel from 320px to 1920px on every browser that has a big enough user base.

In Gforces we use bespoke software to get things running quickly. There is the software the websites run off of and then the software that we use to help us build the sites. I took it upon myself to actively help add to the software that help us build sites (built with node.js (es6), Mithril.js and electron). We also have to use some pretty complex front end javascript and jquery on the sites for a lot of clients to do various, different things.

#### Personal details:

Key I.T. Skills: Node.js, Javascript, Jquery, React.js, Express.js, ES6, Backbone.js, Chai, Angular

1, CSS, Less, SCSS, HTML, Mithril.js, gulp, Web Design, Web Development, Photoshop, Responsive websites, Programming, Python, Django, C#, Java,

MySQL, TDD, Graphics Design, DNS, Heroku, Cloud, Problem Solving.

**Other:** Vue.js, Cloud Foundry, Heroku, AWS, Extreme Programming, social media.

Interests: Coding, Node.js, React.js, Web Development, Web Design, Fitness, Nutrition,

Films, Socializing, Graphic Design, Photography, French Language, Traveling,

Experimenting, Learning New things, Problem Solving, Challenges.

References are available on request:

## Adam Jackson - Director: Research, Innovation and Incubation at

## Canopy Cloud

- Email: adam@adamjackson.org.uk

- Email: adam.jackson@canopy-cloud.com (Company email)

## Romain Barissat - Technology and Innovation leader

- Email: romain@barissat.com

- Email: <a href="mailto:romain.barissat@atos.net">romain.barissat@atos.net</a> (Company email)

## Georgi Barzev - Canopy Cloud Engineering

- Email: glbarzev@yahoo.com
- Email: <a href="mailto:georgi.barzev@canopy-cloud.com">georgi.barzev@canopy-cloud.com</a> (Company email)
- Email: <a href="mailto:georgi.barzev@atos.net">georgi.barzev@atos.net</a> (Company email)

# Robbie Avni - Trainee Firefighter at London Fire Brigade

( Used to be at Canopy Cloud )

- Email: robster113@gmail.com